https://www.mattek.com/privacy-policy/

Privacy Policy and Disclaimer
This website is owned and published by MatTek Corporation.
To ensure that you get the most from our website, we are committed to optimizing the site to match your needs, so it is easier for you to find the content and services most relevant to your work. We endeavor to exceed the strict privacy practices required by the United States CAN-SPAM Act, and the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and e-Privacy Regulation. If, however, you would like to make a query regarding our privacy policy, please contact us.
What you can find in this Privacy Policy
Your Personal Information and How We Collect It
Your Personal Information and How We May Use It
Your Personal Information and How We May Share It
Your Personal Information and How You Share It
How You Can Access, Update or Limit Your Personal Information
How We Can Makes Changes to This Policy
How You Can Contact Us About This Policy
Your Personal Information and How We Collect It
Information You Provide
We collect information you provide to us through our website which is owned and operated by MatTek Corporation. We collect your information when you create an account, subscribe to our email list, download digital materials (e.g. infographics, technical papers, PDFs etc.), sign-up for a webinar or otherwise communicate with us through our website.
The data we collect from you can include personal information. Personal information is data that can be used to identify an individual (such as first and last name, e-mail address, address, telephone number etc.). Furthermore, to ensure that you have a genuine interest in our content, products and services, we may also ask for work-related information such as your job title, your company name, technologies you use, your area of work or industry, the type of business you work for or own, and your scientific interests. We do this to ensure that we are providing you with information that is relevant to you and your field of study or work. At no point will we ask for any “sensitive” information such as religious beliefs, political affiliation, racial or ethnic origin or any other information that does not pertain to your activity or interest in MatTek’s products, services, or its technology.
Once registration is complete no further information is required for access to this site.
Information We Collect
To optimize our website, match content to your needs and deliver a more personalized user experience, MatTek Corporation also automatically collects information regarding your use of our website. When visiting us online, we log information about your visit and also use tracking mechanisms such as cookies, pixels and scripts to collect information about your interaction with our websites or emails. These can be used to provide you with additional information that is relevant to your work or scientific areas of interest.
Cookies are digital text files placed on your computer. Using cookies is a common practice. We may place cookies on your computer to allow us to recognize you on our websites when you visit us, to measure online traffic, to present you with relevant products or services, or to customize your experience. We use session cookies to make navigating our website easier, and they expire when you close your browser. Additionally, tracking cookies are used to help us understand how you use our website, they enhance your user experience, and they remain on your computer or device for an extended period of time.
Your browser may include settings that allow you to block cookies or be notified when cookies are being used. Please be aware that if you block or remove cookies, certain features and functions of our websites may be unavailable or may not operate optimally.
Pixels are small graphic images placed in web pages and e-mail messages. They may be used to count the number of visitors to our websites, to monitor how users navigate our websites, or to verify how many articles or links were viewed.
Scripts are used to collect information about your interactions with our websites. They are temporarily downloaded on your computer from our server, or the server of a third-party we work with. They are active while you are connected to our websites, and are deleted or deactivated thereafter. We do not install or download any software to your computer as part of your user experience.
Information from Other Sources
We may also collect or purchase information from other scientific industry sources, such as scientific organizations, research conferences, academic institutions, scientific directories, etc. Your personal information is only collected and stored in our databases if it is publicly available and there is a clear link between your area of work and the content, products, and services that we offer. We may also combine this information with information we have already collected about you in order to understand your needs better and provide you with a better user experience.
If you are a resident of the European Union or the United States and all the information we have collected about you is from third-party scientific sources, we will only communicate with you on a trial basis with a limited number of attempts before we remove your information from our database. We will also only contact you about MatTek content and topics that you have shown interest in, or about MatTek products that you have purchased in the past which have been deemed relevant to you and your industry, job, scientific interests or area of work. If we see that you have not engaged with our communications or digital content, we will remove your personal information from our database. If you do engage with our communications and digital content before the end of our trial period, we will consider you an active contact for as long as you continue to engage with our content and our websites in the future, or until you choose to unsubscribe from future communications. We offer a means of unsubscribing on every communication that we send to you and through our privacy policy <link>.  If you would like to know more about how we engage with you, please contact us.
Your Personal Information and How We May Use it
The personal information gathered about you is used for a variety of purposes. The first is to build up a demographic profile of our subscribers, allowing us to better match our content and services to your interests. Obviously, the more accurate the information you provide, the better we can do this. For this reason, we encourage you to regularly update your profile to provide us with the most accurate information possible.
In addition, we may use your personal information for other purposes that include:
Facilitating, managing, personalizing and improving your online experience;
Responding to your comments, questions and requests, providing customer service, sending you informational notices, and contacting you if we need to obtain or provide additional information;
Managing your online account, including purchases, orders, payments, returns, and exchanges;
Sending you technical notices, updates, security alerts, support and administrative messages;
Communicating with you about products, services, offers, promotions, coupons, newsletters, events and providing information that we think will be of interest to you;
Conducting research and analysis, including surveys about current services and products or about potential new products and services;
Preventing and addressing fraud, breach of policies or terms, and threats or harm; and
Sending you advertisements and communicating with you regarding services, products, and events we think may interest you
Your Personal Information and How We May Share it
Information Shared With Our Service Providers
We may disclose your information to other companies to ensure the smooth provision of products and services that you have purchased or requested from us. If you have made a purchase or request with us your data will be principally used to provide you with your purchase or request as well as your registration or other services and facilities. This includes third-party service providers that assist us with processing credit card payments, webinar platforms that host our online events or customer relationship management applications where we house your information. These service providers are prohibited from using your personal information for any other purpose(s) than to provide the services we have contracted them to perform.
Information Shared With Our Subsidiary
Your details may also be shared between MatTek Corporation, the parent company, and MatTek In Vitro Life Science Laboratories (MatTek IVLSL), its wholly-owned subsidiary located in Bratislava, Slovakia. MatTek IVLSL is also subject to the data management practices and terms of this privacy policy.
Your Personal Information and How You Share It
Our websites may include features, such as product reviews or comment sections, that allow you to freely submit your personal information that can be viewed by others.  We and others can store, display, reproduce, publish, distribute, or otherwise use such information in any format, and there is no guarantee that we will attribute the content to you.  Keep in mind that if you post information on our websites, others can access and share that information with third-parties as well.
How You Can Access, Update or Limit Your Personal Information
Accessing and Updating Your Personal Information
We have designed our website so that it is easy for you to access and update the personal information that you shared with us. Individual eNewsletters, email communications and third-party communications can be immediately unsubscribed from by clicking an unsubscribe link within them. Please note that your opt-out will not affect subsequent subscriptions or non-promotional communications from us, such as administrative and service announcements. You can download and delete your personal data on our Privacy Tools page. If you require further assistance updating your details please contact us.
You are also entitled to be informed about all the information MatTek Corporation collects about you. You are entitled to receive and review the information. You may also request to have MatTek Corporation change information about you that is held by us and that is incorrect.
Limiting Collection of Your Personal Information
Cookies can be disabled or removed using tools available as part of most commercial browsers. In some instances, a browser may include settings that allow you to block cookies from being placed on your hard drive. Be aware that if you disable or remove cookies and similar technologies, some parts of our website may not work properly. Also, if you revisit our website from a different computer or browser, you may not be able to limit browser-based tracking technologies in the same way.
Our website uses third-party web analytics services, such as Google Analytics, to help us analyze how visitors use our website. To learn more about opting out of being tracked by Google Analytics, click here.
How We Can Make Changes to This Policy
If at any point we decide to use your personally identifiable information in any way other than described in this privacy policy, we will notify you by way of email or by providing 30 days notice on the website. Please note that we retain the right to change this policy at any time. MatTek Corporation continues to invest in the best quality security available and we do our utmost to protect visitor privacy. If you have any queries regarding this privacy policy or the way we collect and gather personal information, please contact us.
How You Can Contact Us About This Policy
If you have any requests regarding your personal information, or if you have questions about this privacy policy, please submit your questions via email to our privacy officer or send a letter to the Privacy Officer at MatTek Corporation, 200 Homer Avenue, Ashland, MA 01721, or call us at 508-881-6771.
(Updated May 29, 2018)
Get the latest
Get MatTek offers and updates delivered to your inbox.
AboutProducts
Tissue Models
EpiAirway™EpiAlveolar™EpiCorneal™EpiDerm™EpiDermFT™EpiGingival™EpiIntestinal™EpiOcular™EpiOral™EpiVaginal™MelanoDerm™MelanomaPsoriasis Back
Primary Cells & Media
Normal Human Epidermal KeratinocytesNormal Human MelanocytesNormal Human Dermal FibroblastsNormal Human Bronchial Epithelial CellsNormal Human Bronchial FibroblastsHuman Immune CellsNormal Human Corneal Epithelial Cells Back
Cultureware
Multi-Well PlatesGlass Bottom DishesChambered Cell Culture Slides Back
Back
Services
Toxicology
Skin Irritation (OECD TG 439)Skin Irritation (MTT ET-50)Skin Corrosion (OECD TG 431)PhototoxicityEye Irritation Test (OECD TG 492)Eye Irritation (MTT ET-50)Oral IrritationInhalation Toxicology Back
Back
Applications
Dermal
Skin Irritation (OECD TG 439)Skin Irritation (MTT ET-50)Skin Corrosion (OECD TG 431)Skin Irritation Medical Device Extracts (ISO 10993)PhototoxicitySkin HydrationAnti-AgingSkin LighteningPigmentation StudiesDrug Delivery (Dermal)GenotoxicityAnti-Psoriasis Drug ScreeningAnti-Melanoma Drug ScreeningTumor Invasion Back
Ocular
Eye Irritation Test (OECD TG 492)Eye Irritation (MTT ET-50) Back
Oral
Oral IrritationAbsorptionOral CandidiasisDrug Delivery (Oral Mucosal) Back
Intestinal
Epithelial RestitutionIntestinal FibrosisDrug MetabolismDrug Delivery (Intestinal)Inflammation Back
Respiratory
Respiratory InfectionDrug DeliveryInhalation ToxicologyInflammation and Fibrosis Back
Vaginal
Vaginal InflammationVaginal Microbicide TestingFeminine HygieneSTD Infection Back
Immune Cell
Allergenicity TestingMicrobial InfectionBasic DC Research Back
Back
ReferencesNewsStore
HAND SANITIZER now available in our online store Dismiss
